Guide to the Nuclear Fallout Shelter Collection, 1959-1961.
Nuclear Fallout Shelter Collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Nuclear Fallout Shelter Collection, 1959-1961.
8584
0.1
Printed materials.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Collection contains 16 pamphlets, booklets and newsletters on how to prepare for and survive a nuclear attack issued primarily by federal and state government agencies.
In the late 1950s and early 1960s, Cold War tensions and threat of nuclear war convinced government leaders in the United States that millions of lives could be saved by the construction of home fallout shelters. How-to booklets proliferated, instructing people in the fine points of building their own shelters, family preparations, first aid, and what to do in an emergency.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Collection contains 16 pamphlets, booklets and newsletters on how to prepare for and survive a nuclear attack issued primarily by federal and state government agencies.
SUBJECTS
Subjects:
Disaster preparedness.; Nuclear bomb shelters.; Nuclear disasters.; Nuclear energy.; Nuclear energy -- United States.; Nuclear energy -- Safety measures.; Nuclear warfare.; Nuclear warfare -- Safety measures.; Nuclear warfare -- Social aspects.; Survival
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Individual and Family Preparedness, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Executive Office of the President/Office of Civil and Defense Mobilization
- Emergency Sanitation at Home, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Department of Defense/Office of Civil Defense
- MPF, Multi-Purpose Food: a simple answer to the food storage problem for civil defense, 1960's (Box 1, Folder 3)
- The Family Fallout Shelter, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Stapled inside the front cover is a list - "Civil Defense Information: You Should Have the Following Items on Hand At All Times"
- Responsibilities of the Local Government, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- This is Your Community Emergency Plan, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  California Disaster Office
- Fire Fighting for Householders, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Department of Defense
- Personal Preparedness in the Nuclear Age, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Office of Civil and Defense Mobilization
- A Family Action Program, home protection exercises, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  Executive Office of the President
- Emergency Actions to Save Lives, 1960's (Box 1, Folder 10)
- First aid, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Facts about Fallout protection, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Ten for Survival: Survive Nuclear Attack, 1960's (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Fallout Protection: What to know and do about nuclear attack, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- When The Warning Sounds - 2 business size cards with information, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)